Finding Aid for Almon Watson McCall papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Almon Watson McCall papers 1924-1970
McCall, Almon Watson, 1905-1970.
851742 Aa 2
Newspaperman in Grand Haven, Michigan, papers contain correspondence, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and other material relating to his newspaper career.
3 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donor: 5427
No further additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Grand Haven, Ottawa County newspaperman.
Contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and other material relating to his newspaper career, particularly his activities with the American Press Institute, the Michigan League of Home Dailies, the Michigan Press Association and the Associated Press; also student papers and manuscripts of articles and stories, and historical data on Grand Haven and Spring Lake.
Subjects:
Associated Press.; Grand Haven (Mich.); Journalists--Michigan--Grand Haven.; McCall, Almon Watson, 1905-1970.; Michigan League of Home Dailies.; Michigan Press Association.; Michigan Press Institute.; Newspaper editors--Michigan--Grand Haven.; Ottawa County (Mich.); Spring Lake (Mich.)
Contributors:
Beukema, John C., 1888-1967.; Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Detzer, Karl, 1891-1987; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Hannah, John A., 1902-1991; Jonkman, Bartel J. (Bartel John), 1884-1955.; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.; Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961.; Mapes, Carl Edgar, 1874-1939.; Tufty, Esther Van Wagoner, d. 1986.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Van Wagoner, Murray Delos, 1898-; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Ziegler, Charles M., 1888-1959.
- Correspondence
  - Undated 1924-1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933 (Box 1)
  - 1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Box 1)
  - January-April 1937 (Box 1)
  - May-December 1937 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1938 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1938 (Box 1)
  - 1939-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941 (Box 1)
  - January-May 1942 (Box 1)
  - June 1-15,1942 (Box 1)
  - June 16-30,1942 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1942 (Box 1)
  - 1945-1947 (Box 1)
  - 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950 (Box 1)
  - 1951 (Box 1)
  - 1952 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1953 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1953 (Box 1)
  - January-March 1954 (Box 1)
  - April-December 1954 (Box 1)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - 1957-1967 (Box 1)
  - 1968 (Box 1)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 1)
- Papers
  - 1929-1969 concerning the activities of the McCall family in the newspaper business (Box 1)
  - 1969 concerning McCall's selection as "Editor of the Year" (Box 1)
  - Lists of editorials written 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - Lists of editorials written 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - 1932 concerning the Michigan League of Home Dailies (Box 1)
  - 1942 concerning the Associated Press meeting held in Grand Haven (Box 1)
  - 1953 concerning the American Press Institute, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1962 concerning the American Press Institute, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Letters 1942-1945 from soldiers in World War II (Box 1)
  - 1939 concerning the Michigan Press Association meeting in Grand Haven (Box 1)
  - 1945-1961 concerning the Michigan Press Association (Box 1)
  - 1969 concerning Karl Detzer (Box 1)
- Miscellanea
  - Newspaper clippings 1937-1970, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Student papers undated, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Short story 1925 "The Man Who. Meddled with Nature" (Box 2)
  - Central Normal Life 1924 (containing article by McCall) (Box 2)
  - Central Normal Life 1925 (containing article by McCall) (Box 2)
  - Student papers written at Northwestern University, 11 folders (Box 2)
  - Manuscript 1929 of "An Intellectual Adventure" written by McCall (Box 2)
  - Published articles by McCall 1924-1932 (Box 2)
  - Story on Joe Schnitzer by McCall (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 2)
- Grand Haven File
  - Chamber of Commerce undated (Box 2)
  - Chamber of Commerce 1938-1943 (Box 2)
  - Chamber of Commerce 1944-1952 (Box 2)
  - The Grand Haven Industrial Survey 1957 (Box 2)
  - Grand Haven Harbor, 2 folders; 1 volumes (Box 3)
  - Grand Haven Musical Fountain (Box 3)
  - North Ottawa Community Hospital (Box 3)
  - 75th Anniversary issue of the Tribune (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets, 4 folders (Box 3)
- Spring Lake File
  - Spring Lake Improvement Association 1954-1957, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - 100th Anniversary issue of the Tribune (Box 3)
  - Miscellanea (Box 3)
- Photographs
  The Photograph series includes one photo (1949) of McCall receiving an award; and aerial photographs (1969) of the Grand Haven-Spring Lake, Michigan harbor area.
  - Photographs (Box 3)